<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Security and programming stuff</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content on Security and programming stuff</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-uk</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How not to write tests - TDD in .NET</title><link>/posts/how-not-to-write-tests/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/how-not-to-write-tests/</guid><description>Journey Writing no tests Nobody starts programming with writing tests right away. You always start with a Hello World followed by heaps of pretty bad and untestable code. (I still remember coding a Tic-tac-toe game by writing thousands of ifs for every possible move.)
Let’s fantasize, things go different way. That after just one project everyone discovers the idea of unit testing. Just imagine everyone creates tests for every piece of code they write.</description></item><item><title>Hacking buttons - part 2</title><link>/posts/hacking-buttons-p2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hacking-buttons-p2/</guid><description>In this post I will briefly write about two small projects I recently created. Both made use of remote controllers and both ended as pretty small. Considering the size, I thought I’d write about them in just one post.
LED remote controller repair Inspiration for the first project emerged out of necessity. One day I decided to repair the LED strip remote controller. The top cover, visible on the left, fell off and made it impossible to push any buttons.</description></item><item><title>Binary patching - creating Tibia MultiClient</title><link>/posts/binary-patching-tibia-multiclient/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/binary-patching-tibia-multiclient/</guid><description>Childhood dreams During some of my first school years I used to play an MMORPG game. It had a reputation for having a lot of cheats for it. (Bad reputation still counts as reputation, right?)
People have created all kinds of software for it. Some small and harmless programs enabled you to change the outfit of your character client-side. Others, much clever ones, made trees invisible, so you could see items hidden behind them.</description></item><item><title>First 3D Printout</title><link>/posts/first-3d-printout/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/first-3d-printout/</guid><description>Dishwasher 101 Your browser does not support the video tag. You know this meme, right? Something similar happened to me once when I unloaded the dishwasher. With the dishwasher’s door opened I also opened a cupboard next to it. I guess nobody has tested to open both things at the same time before.
Everything broke. The mechanism fell into pieces and scattered across the whole kitchen. The door fell on the floor, and some plastic parts broke off.</description></item><item><title>Magic box</title><link>/posts/magic-box/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/magic-box/</guid><description>Make gifts for people Don’t make stuff because you want to make money — it will never make you enough money. And don’t make stuff because you want to get famous — because you will never feel famous enough. Make gifts for people — and work hard on making those gifts in the hope that those people will notice and like the gifts.
Maybe they will notice how hard you worked, and maybe they won’t — and if they don’t notice, I know it’s frustrating.</description></item><item><title>Hacking buttons</title><link>/posts/hacking-buttons/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hacking-buttons/</guid><description>Idea You’d think when living far from the city centre and near the underground station, there’s plenty of parking space? Nothing could be further from the truth.
However, something is even more baffling. Most of the street at which I live is closed by a road barrier which could be opened using a remote control. There’s no point in using it though because past the barrier there’re even fewer free parking spaces.</description></item><item><title>RE for Beginners Julia - write-up</title><link>/posts/julia-write-up/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2019 18:41:58 +0100</pubDate><guid>/posts/julia-write-up/</guid><description>Write-up intro Let&amp;rsquo;s make a write-up of the easiest of the easiest reverse engineering challenges (not even entry CTF level).
I will show you how I, as a total beginner, approached it and how I made it through.
For the reversing tool I will be using Binary Ninja ($149) since it&amp;rsquo;s much more affordable than IDA Pro ($589).
Goal The goal as with many other crackme challenges is to find the correct password.</description></item></channel></rss>